iolo.com 2019-06-24

# IOLO TECHNOLOGIES, LLC PRIVACY POLICY - iolo technologies

iolo technologies, LLC ( **“iolo,” “our,” “us” or “we”** ) is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy applies to all websites owned or operated by iolo, including iolo.com. This Privacy Policy governs our data collection, processing and usage practices. It also describes your choices regarding use of, access to, erasure of and correction of your personal information. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the products or websites of our business partners, affiliates or to any other third parties, even if their products or websites are linked to or from our websites. You can find more information about how we work with our business partners and affiliates below.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or how we collect, use or process your personal information or how you may access, erase and correct your personal information, please contact us using the contact details described in section 12 – Contacting us.

**1\. Definitions**

We use some terms in this Privacy Policy, that we want to highlight for you.

“business partner(s)” means any subcontractor, vendor or other entity with whom we have a business relationship to provide products, services, payment processing services, or information.  
“financial information” means credit card or other payment card information, personal financial account information, and other financial information you provide when you purchase our products and/or services.  
“personal information” means information which identifies you or which combined may identify you, such as your name, telephone number, home address, email address, Internet Protocol (IP) address, Media Access Control (MAC) address, location data and any other information that would permit us to identify you either online or physically. It also may include information about free trial downloads of our products or purchases of our products or services. Personal information also includes financial information.

**2\. Information We Collect and How We Collect It**

We may ask you to provide personal information when you:

  * Visit our websites;
  * Create an iolo account;
  * Use our products;
  * Request services, support, or information;
  * Download a trial product;
  * Purchase our products or services;
  * Input activation keys;
  * Purchase support services or other services;
  * Participate in sweepstakes, surveys or other advertising activities;
  * Subscribe to newsletters and, promotional emails;
  * Interact with social media;
  * Contact us or provide feedback or comments; or
  * Apply for a job.

**2.1 Visit our websites**

We will collect information when you visit our websites, including the pages you view, the links you click, and other actions you take in connection with the iolo websites and services. We also collect information from the browser you used to come to our websites, such as your IP address, MAC address, browser type and language, operating system version, search terms you enter, the date and time when you accessed our websites or services, how long you stay on our websites or use our services, one or more cookies that uniquely identify your browser, the Uniform Resource Locator (“URL”) of the website that referred you to our website and if you click on a link on our website, which URL that link takes you to away from our website.

**2.2 Create an iolo account**

You can browse the iolo websites without creating an account, but an account will be created when you purchase our products or services. Information in your account will include your customer ID, contact and financial information such as name, email, billing and shipping address, telephone number, payment information, VAT ID and your purchase history.

**2.3 Request services, support or information**

If you contact us to request support or services, we may request your name, email address, home address and telephone number. If you are contacting us on behalf of your employer, we also may collect your business or company information or other information.  
In addition to contact information, we may ask you for information about which product you are using, which version of Windows or other computer programs you are using, the nature of your issue, and any other information pertinent to the support request (“technical information”). If you permit us or our business partner to remotely access your device to perform support services, iolo and its business partner also will receive technical non-personal information regarding your computer specifications directly from your device.

**2.4 Download a trial product or purchase our products or services**

If you request a free trial version of our products, whether through our website or a business partner’s website, you will be asked to provide your email address so that we can send you the activation key.

If you purchase one of our products or services, whether through our website or a business partner’s website, you will be asked for personal information, including, your name, telephone number, email, mailing, billing and shipping addresses, credit card or PayPal information. Your personal information will be available in “My Account” for any future transactions.

Our System Mechanic product collects technical information from your computer to help optimize its performance, including file names, file paths, and which programs are being used. This technical information is collected anonymously, and is not combined with any personal information.

**2.5 Participate in sweepstakes, surveys or other advertising activities**

If you enter a sweepstakes offered by iolo, we will collect the personal information described in the rules of that sweepstake. If you participate in a survey, we will collect the information you chose to provide in the survey. We collect personal information when you view or click on an advertisement we display on our affiliates’ websites (for more information about how this works, see section 8 – Information collected through cookies and similar tracking technology.)

**2.6 Subscribe to newsletters and promotional emails**

When you receive newsletters or promotional emails from iolo, we may use cookies and web beacons (described below), customized links or other technologies to recognize you, to determine whether the email has been opened, which links you click, and whether you purchased our products or services. The data is used to help us determine the effectiveness of our communications with you, gather demographic information about our user base, provide you with communications and product and service offerings more tailored to your personal interests, to serve targeted advertising on other websites around the Internet and to provide security. Some iolo products or services may be co-branded and offered in conjunction with another company. If you register for or use such products or services, both iolo and the other company may receive and use information collected in conjunction with the co-branded products or services.

**2.7 Interact with social media**

The iolo website allows users to interface with social media websites such as Facebook, Twitter, Google+ and others. If you choose to “like” our websites or products or share information from the iolo websites to social media websites, those social media websites may collect personal information about you. If you have an account with a social media site, the social media site may connect personal information that you may have provided to that social media site with information regarding your iolo website visit. Social media websites also may allow third-parties to provide us personal information about you, including your name, email address, and other personal information. The data we receive is dependent upon your privacy settings with the social media website. Social media features (such as the Like button) are either hosted by a third-party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it. You should review, and if necessary, adjust your privacy settings on third-party websites and services before linking or connecting them to our website.

If you have an account with a social media website, the interfaces on the iolo website may allow you to log into “My Account” through the social media website such as Google, Yahoo or AOL.

**2.8 Contact us or provide comments or feedback**

When you contact us by telephone, we collect the information you chose to provide us. If you contact us by email, we will collect the same information we collect when you visit our websites and any other information you chose to provide us in the email. If you choose to provide us feedback or comments, iolo will collect the same information it collects when you use our websites. In addition, iolo will collect any personal information you chose to provide along with your feedback or comments. iolo owns that feedback and those comments and may retain that information indefinitely, however iolo will delete any personal information provided with that feedback or comment, unless iolo requires the personal information for another purpose and will then maintain such information for as long as needed for that other purpose.

**2.9 Apply for a job**

Job applicants may be requested to provide information such as educational background, employment experience, job interest and additional personal information such as social security number, other national identification number, passport number, driver’s license number or similar personal identifiers. Unless you instruct us otherwise, we may keep the information you provide us for other future job opportunities at iolo.

**3\. How We Use Your Personal Information and Technical Information**

iolo uses your personal information and technical information to:

  * Complete your transaction for products and/or services that you ordered, to process any refunds or chargebacks, manage disputes or related issues, provide receipts, recover debt and collections, and fulfilling other technical, logistical, financial, tax, legal, compliance, administrative, or back office functions. In support of these uses, iolo and our business partners may share your financial information with banks and other entities that process payment transactions or other financial services;
  * Deliver products, services and support to you;
  * Send communications to you, such as your transaction status (for example, order confirmations or remaining time on products or services), newsletters and other product information;
  * Provide you information about promotional offers, sweepstakes, and surveys offered by or on behalf of iolo;
  * Maintain, protect, and improve our products, services, websites, technologies, communications with you and our relationship with you;
  * Enforce our conditions of sale, website terms and any separate contracts with you;
  * Detect and prevent fraud;
  * Detect and prevent violations of law or legal agreements; and
  * Protect the company and its employees and business partners.

In order to offer you a more consistent and personalized experience in your interactions with iolo, personal information collected through one source may be combined with personal information obtained through other iolo sources, including social media sources.  
We will ask for your consent before using your information for any purpose not set out in this Privacy Policy.

**4\. Disclosing Personal Information**

We may disclose your personal information in connection with a financial audit, law enforcement, national security, fraud prevention, or other legal action (such as a subpoena or court order); as required by law or regulation; or if iolo reasonably believes it is necessary to protect iolo, its customers or the public. In addition, we may share your personal information with business partners that help iolo carry out transactions you request or that help iolo to customize, analyze and improve our communications or relationship with you, and then only with business partners who share iolo’s commitment to protecting your personal information. We also may share your personal information with our business partners to help make our business or that of our business partners’ more responsive to your needs. Except as described in this Privacy Policy, we will not disclose your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes unless you have provided consent.

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy products, subsidiaries, or business units. In such transactions, personal information may be reviewed as part of the business due diligence and generally is one of the transferred business assets but remains subject to the promises made in any pre-existing privacy policy (unless, of course, you consent otherwise). Also, in the event that iolo, or some or all of its assets are acquired, customer information will of course be one of the transferred assets.

Some iolo services are provided by business partners that may be located in different countries than iolo or than where you are calling from. When you purchase support services from iolo, we may provide your personal information along with technical information to our business partners in order to provide the support services you request.

**5\. Your Choices**

**5.1 Updating your information**

iolo wants to help you keep your personal information accurate. If any of your information changes, you can update it by accessing “My Account” from the iolo.com website.

**5.2 Selecting your communication preferences**

At any point, you may unsubscribe from newsletters or marketing materials by clicking on the unsubscribe link that appears at the very bottom of each message you receive from iolo. This link will take you to a web page containing information specific to your email account where you can unsubscribe. Please note that you cannot opt-out of receiving non-promotional messages regarding your account, such as technical notices, purchase confirmations, renewal reminders, or service-related emails.

**5.3 Accessing your information**

Subject to applicable laws, you may have the right to ask iolo to:

  * provide a copy of the personal information that we have collected about you;
  * correct or update your personal information;
  * delete or erase your personal information;
  * restrict or object to the way in which we process your personal information; and
  * withdraw any consent that you may have given to us.

In order to comply with the above requests, we may ask you to provide us with the necessary information to verify your identity. We will respond to legitimate requests within thirty days of the request. In certain instances and subject to applicable laws (including, for example, tax, audit and reporting obligations), we may need to extend our response time or we may not be able fulfill your requests. If we cannot fulfill your requests, we will explain why we cannot do so.

To make these requests or for more information about your rights, please contact our Data Protection Officer at: dpo@iolo.com.

If you are located in Europe, you may learn more about your rights in section 10.1 – Privacy Shield.

**6\. How We Secure Your Information**

iolo is committed to protecting the security of your information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure taking into account the level of risk, the nature of the information and how it is going to be used, such as encryption using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology, passwords, physical security, etc. While we strive to protect your personal information, iolo cannot and does not ensure or warrant that the personal information or private communications you transmit to us will always remain private, and you do so at your own risk.

For your security, you will be required to enter your account name and password to access your “My Account”. You should use strong passwords and maintain the confidentiality of your password and other account credentials. Do not share this information with anyone. If you are sharing a computer with anyone you should always log out before leaving a website or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users.

**7\. Collection and Use of Children’s Personal Information**

iolo takes children’s privacy seriously. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 16 through our websites.

If you are under 18 years of age, please do not submit any personal information through our websites without the express consent and participation of a parent or guardian.

**8\. Information Collected through Cookies and Similar Tracking Technology**

iolo websites and our business partners’ websites use “cookies” and similar tracking technologies (such as web beacons, tags, scripts and device identifiers). We may receive reports from business partners based on use of these technologies. These reports may provide this information on an individual as well as on an aggregated basis. Aggregate information is anonymous and may include demographic, usage, and sales information.

**8.1 Cookies**

A cookie is a text file that is either stored in your computer’s memory temporarily and automatically deleted when you close your browser (a session cookie) or placed on your hard drive (a persistent cookie) by a web page server. A persistent cookie is not deleted when the browser is closed. iolo uses both session cookies and persistent cookies. While iolo cookies do not save any personal information, they do save the serial number of any product licenses, which can be connected to your personal information such as email address, billing address and IP address. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. Please refer to your web browser for more information. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to sign in or use other interactive features of iolo websites and services that depend on cookies.

We use cookies to:

  * save your preferences and other information on your computer in order to save you time by eliminating the need to repeatedly enter the same information;
  * improve our websites;
  * display personalized (targeted) content and appropriate iolo product offerings on your later visits to our websites and to our partners’ and affiliates’ websites;
  * allow you to sign in to our services and to help personalize and customize your online experience;
  * gather demographic information about our users;
  * offer our products and services to you;
  * tailor product discounts and purchase links;
  * monitor the success of marketing programs;
  * provide analytics regarding the use of our website, products and services; and
  * provide security to attempt to identify and prevent fraud.

Because iolo relies on third-party advertising networks who may track you across websites over time for advertising purposes, we are not able to respond to your selection of the “Do Not Track”” option provided by your browser. We cannot advise on whether your selection of “Do Not Track” option will have any effect on the collection of cookie information by the third-parties who collect such cookie information on our websites.

**8.2 Web Beacons**

A “web beacon” is an electronic image that can be used to recognize a cookie on your computer when you view a web page or email. Our business partners use web beacons on our websites, in our emails, in our advertisements on other websites (including social media), and in our advertisements contained in third party emails sent to you. Web beacons help us measure the effectiveness of our websites and our advertising in various ways for example, by counting the number of individuals who visit our websites from a particular advertisement or who make a purchase from our websites after viewing a particular advertisement as well as by telling us when a web page is viewed and providing a description of the page where the web beacon is placed. Web beacons also help us measure the effectiveness of our email campaigns, for example, by counting the number of individuals who open or act upon an email message, determining when an email message is opened and determining how many times an email message is forwarded. This helps us send more relevant advertisements to our users and on the websites most visited by you.  
Unlike cookies, you cannot decline web beacons. However, setting your browser to decline cookies may help prevent web beacons tracking your activity.

**8.3 Analytic Tools**

We may use tools such as Google Analytics to better understand who is using our websites and how they are using them. These tools may use cookies and web beacons to save and collect information such as time of visit, pages visited, time spent on each page of the website, IP address, and type of operating system used. We may use this information to manage and improve our websites and to improve your experience with our websites. You can learn how to opt-out of Google Analytics tracking software at this website: http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

**9\. Third-Party Websites and Services**  
Please be aware that other websites that you may access through our websites or from which you access our websites may collect personal information about you. The information practices of those third-party websites linked to or from iolo.com are not covered by this Privacy Policy.

Please be aware that, in providing services on iolo’s behalf, our business partners may collect personal information about you.

**10\. Retention, Storing and Transfer of Personal Information**

We will maintain your personal information for a period of two years from your last contact with us, unless we need to maintain it longer to comply with legal, tax, audit or other reporting requirements, and for the detection and prevention of fraud or other unlawful behavior.

Personal information collected may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which iolo or its business partners maintain facilities, and these countries may have laws that are different from those of your country of residence. By using iolo products and services, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country.

**10.1 Privacy Shield**

iolo participates in and has certified compliance with both the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. iolo is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Frameworks, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program please visit [Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

iolo is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf, unless we prove we are not in any way responsible for the event giving rise to the harm.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, iolo is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, iolo may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

In compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, iolo commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy should first contact iolo’s Data Protection Officer at:

iolo technologies, LLC  
150 South Los Robles Ave.  
Pasadena, CA 91101 U.S.A.  
dpo@iolo.com

Finally, if we cannot resolve your complaint directly, EU and Swiss individuals with residual privacy complaints may bring a complaint before [JAMS EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Dispute Resolution](https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-claim). Under limited circumstances, EU and Swiss individuals may request the binding arbitration option before the Privacy Shield Panel. Please contact iolo’s Data Protection Officer to be directed to the relevant parties.

**11\. Changes to Our Privacy Policy Regarding Customer and Online User Information**

We will occasionally update this Privacy Policy. When we post changes to this Privacy Policy, we will revise the Effective Date at the end of this paragraph. If there are material changes to this Privacy Policy or in how iolo will use your personal information, we will notify you by prominently posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change. We encourage you to periodically review this Policy to be informed of how iolo is protecting your personal information.

Effective Date: May 25, 2018.  
Please click here for archived versions.

**12\. Contacting Us**

If you would like to contact us for any reason regarding our privacy practices, please write us at the following address: Privacy Administrator, iolo technologies, LLC, 150 South Los Robles Ave., Pasadena, CA 91101 U.S.A. or via email at privacypolicy@iolo.com.
